

# DAMJAN KOLEVSKI

# Product Design Engineer

**4** +389 70 277 552

□ damjan.kolevski@gmail.com

△ damjankol.github.io/portfolio

with a bachelor's degree of Industrial Design in Mechanical Engineering, and five years of work experience in that field, followed by an academy of UX Design, and over one year of work experience on that position.

His strongest competences are: Research, Prototyping, Front End Programming, New product development, CAD, Mechanical Engineering, Project management, Developing department procedures, Design and execution of Manufacturing Technologies, Continuous improvement (Kaizen), LEAN culture (5S, Kanban), On-time results, International teamwork, Dynamic workflow.

Industries he experiences: IT, Healthcare, Smart Manufacturing, Sport, Hospitality.

Personally, he is described as: committed, honest, reliable, enthusiastic, creative, details-oriented, communicative, adaptable, patient, tolerant.

# DIGITAL COMPETENCE

- Adobe XD, Figma, InVision, Miro (Information Architecture, Wireframes, Prototypes)
- Photoshop, Illustrator (Graphic Design)
- HTML, CSS, JS (Front End Programming)
- Solidworks, AutoCAD, MAYA, CATIA (3D assembly modelling & 2D technical drawing)
- ProCast, Matlab, Adams (Dynamic simulations)
- 3ds MAX (Animation)

# WORK EXPERIENCE

# **UX** Designer

TRIGAMA INTERNATIONAL, Industry: IT

Jan. 2022 - present, Prague

- Scope: Ideation, Research, Prototyping (in Figma)
- Field: Apps and software
- Industries: Automotive, Manufacturing, Dig. Marketing

### **UX Design Engineer**

ATS GLOBAL, Industry: IT, SaaS, Industry 4.0 Apr. 2021 – Feb. 2022, Skopje

- User Researching, User Tests (with Userlytics)
- Mapping User Flows (with Miro)
- Designing Wireframes (with InVision)
- Designing Prototypes (with Figma)
- Implementing Web Accessibility (WCAG 2.0)
- Planning a development of Design System
- Working in Agile environment (with Azure DevOps)

#### R&D / CAD Mechanical Engineer

CRANFIELD FOUNDRY, Industry: Foundry Jan. 2019 - Sep. 2020, Probishtip

#### **Development Engineer**

CASTINVEST, Industry: Foundry Feb. 2018 - Oct. 2018, Skopje

# **Business Developer**

REGEMAT 3D, Industry: Healthcare Aug. 2017 - Jan. 2018, Granada

#### **Assistant to CEO**

KOPLAST, Industry: Plastic Mar. 2015 – Jul. 2017, Skopje

#### **Graphic Designer & Events Organizer**

Macedonian Canoe Federation, Industry: Sport Mar. 2014 – present (part-time), Skopje

# **EDUCATION**

### **BRAINSTER Academy of UX/UI Design**

Jul. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Pre-program/Graphic Design (Photoshop, Illustrator)
- Fundamentals of UX/UI Design
- Tools: AdobeXD, Figma, InVision (Information Architecture, Wireframes, Prototypes)
- Design Systems, Responsive Design
- Front End Programming (HTML, CSS, JS)
- Storytelling, Pitching

### **MOTIVA Management Training**

Feb. 2013 - Mar. 2013

Communication Skills; Developing and Managing Effective Teams; Entrepreneurship, Developing SMEs, Writing Business Plan; Financial Mgmt.; Leadership and Business Negotiation; Strategic Mgmt. and Business Ethics; Export Marketing; Presentation Skills; Change Mgmt.; Human Resources Mgmt.; Quality Mgmt.

# University Ss. Cyril & Methodius in Skopje, Bachelor of Mech. Engineering in Industrial Design

Sep. 2011 - Jan. 2015

- Mechanical Engineering,
- New Product Development,
- 3D assembly modelling & 2D technical drawing (Solidworks, AutoCAD, MAYA, CATIA),
- Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing,
  Design for Manufacturability, Material Properties
- Graphic Design (Photoshop),
- Dynamic Simulation (Matlab, Adams),
- Animation (3ds MAX),
- Web Design/HTML/CSS (Dreamweaver)

#### **Vocational Courses**

- IBM: Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner (August 2021)
- IDF: User Research Methods and Best Practices (July 2021)
- IDF: Conducting Usability Testing (June 2021)

# PERSONAL INFORMATION

- age: Millennial
- languages: English (fluent), Spanish (intermediate), French (beginner), Macedonian (mother tongue) Bulgarian (fluent), Croatian (fluent), Serbian (fluent).
- driver's license: B category (active driver)
- hobbies: Painting, Photography, Architecture, Folklore, Ecology, Humanitarian Volunteering, Tennis, Skiing, Volleyball, Hiking, White-water kayaking, Karate, Scouting, Dancing, Ice-skating, Table-tennis, Billiard, Ultimate Frisbee, Playing Piano, Flute...